我今天要带客户看房
I have to show a house today,
直接在卢克的橄榄球赛上见吧
so see you guys at Luke's football games.
我累死了才不去
I'm too tired to go.
我明天有期中考试
I have a midterm tomorrow
很有可能会挂  我昨晚学习到很晚
which I'll probably fail. And I was up really late studying.
是真的呢  我昨晚就这样吃惊到很晚
She was. I was up really late doing this.
没必要费劲跑一趟了  我今天不想参加
Don't even bother coming. I'm quitting today.
我受够了队里一个家伙总是取笑我
I'm sick of this guy in the team always making fun of me.
他那是嫉妒
He's just jealous because
因为你才是给记分牌上加分的人
you're the one who puts points on the board.
为什么呢
Why?
-因为你负责记分  -负责记分
- Because you run the scoreboard. - ...run the scoreboard.
我也不去了
I'm out, too.
但你的同学们都会去呢
But all your classmates will be there.
我们一整周都互不理睬
We ignore each other all week.
周末歇歇也好啊
It's nice to have a little break on the weekends.
老天  我从没见过这么多"被拒者"
Geez, I've never seen such a bunch of no-getters.
造词成功
Coined it!
记住  保持乐观心态
Remember, keep a positive attitude,
好事自然会发生
and good things will happen.
我每次带客户看房都带着两样东西
Two things I bring to every open house --
我的幸运钢笔和微笑
my lucky pen and a smile.
我整个月都没卖出一套房
I haven't sold a house all month.
你们有听到我说"我不干了"吗  没有
Do you see me saying "I'm done"? Never.
因为邓菲家字典里没有"完了"这个词
Because there is no "Done" in Dunphy.
我们比赛时见
I'll see you guys at the game.
邓菲家字典里也没有"好烦"这个词
Hey, there is no "Umph" in Dunph--
拼法不一样
different spelling!
小卡
Cam!
菲尔  我记得你的特别战术
Yes, Phil, I remember your special play,
但我认为在这样一场重要的赛事上
but I think the triple gull-wing is a little tricky
用三路包抄的战术有点不靠谱
to run at such an important sporting match.
小卡在橄榄球赛季总会有一些
Cam has a number of delightful superstitions
可爱的迷信行为
during the football season.
管用的话就不是迷信行为
Well, they're not superstitions when they work.
好像很科学啊
That seems science-y.
好在今天是最后一场"波以  死爱"
Not sorry that today is the last g-a-m-e.
谢谢  但好教练不需要靠运气
Well, thank you, but good coaches don't need luck.
我们制造运气
We make luck.
我们在"体育活动"中见吧
See you at the athletic endeavor.
我要给歌洛莉亚打电话
I'm going to call Gloria
看她能不能去接莉莉
and see if she can pick up Lily, too,
以防...
you know, just in case...
怎么  你又要犯拖延症
What, you procrastinate again
不跟查理提辞职吗
and not tell Charlie you're quitting?
不是的  我会提的
No, no! I'm gonna do it.
我只是  一想到我告诉他时
I just -- I'm picturing his face when I tell him,
他失望摇头的表情  就觉得
shaking his head in disappointment.
很难开口
It's -- it's hard.
-提就是了  -不行
- Hey, just do it! - No.
我不明白这件事你为什么要这样逼疯自己
I don't know why you're making yourself so crazy over this.
你说得对  你说得对
You're right. You're right.
我  我可不想发疯
I -- I do not want to be crazy.
比赛时见
I'll see you at the game.
歌洛莉亚
Hey, Gloria.
好  米奇  我会去接她
Yes, Mitch, I will pick her up.
太感谢了  好了  再见  莉莉
Thank you so much! All right. Bye, Lily.
祝你和帕特里克发展顺利
Good luck with the whole Patrick situation.
爸爸  你这样让我很丢脸
Dad, you're embarrassing me.
欢迎进入你的人生新阶段  亲爱的
Well, welcome to the rest of your life, sweetheart.
莉莉  跟我说说这个帕特里克的事吧
So, Lily, tell me more about this Patrick.
他喜欢荡秋千  坐在国旗旁边
He likes the swings, he sits by the flag,
而且他可以一直数到一百呢
and he can count to 100.
听起来很完美啊
He sounds like the whole package.
那问题出在哪里
Then what is the problem?
他的眼里没有我
He doesn't notice me.
那就让他注意到你啊
So then make him notice you.
你可不想到九岁那年
You don't want to wake up one morning
醒来发现自己还孤身一人
as a lonely 9-year-old,
心中感叹过去的时光一片空白
wondering where all the time went.
老妈  如果你一会儿去超市
Hey, mom. If you're at the store later,
能买点冰回来吗
could you pick up some ice?
比赛后我需要用
I'm gonna need it for after the game.
真不愧是我的小运动员
My little athlete.
我想试试我卖了自行车换来的冰淇淋机
I want to try out the gelato maker I traded my bike for.
每次我都想太多了
Lures me in every time.
好  再见
Oh, okay. Bye.
爸  你可以在下个红绿灯把我放下来
Dad, you can just drop me at the next light.
我可以从那走过去
I can walk from there,
正要我需要给菲尔打个电话
and I got to call Phil anyway.
你昨天也这样
You did the same thing yesterday.
为什么啊  你怎么啦
Why? What's going on with you?
-你又开始抽烟了吗  -没有  不是
- You smoking again? - No! No.
我只是  我不想让大家注意到
I just -- I don't want to put a spotlight
我是老板的女儿
on the fact that I'm the boss's daughter.
这会让人讨厌我
It makes people resent me.
-这里就好  谢谢老爸  -好吧
- This is good. Thanks, dad. - Yeah.
-再见  -再见
- Bye. - Bye.
看得出来那让你很苦恼啊
I can see that bothers you.
是啊  自己的孩子
Well, yeah, your own kid,
觉得被看到和你在一起很丢脸
embarrassed to be seen with you,
你能理解吗
you know what I mean?
-你一辈子都在...  -到这里就好
- You spend your whole life...  - Here's fine.
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
■
翻译：小饭  罂粟无果  二千  萌驮  丁小七
时间轴：MH    校对：olivia_xuxu   后期&总监：瓜瓜
家  庭
摩  登
第五季 第九集
上个月  我在法学院的一位同学邀请我
Last month, a law-school classmate offered me a job
去他的法律援助协会工作
at his legal aid society,
直觉告诉我  我得接受
and I just knew I had to take it.
我写了封信解释这个情况
And I explained that in a letter
并打算偷偷放在查理的办公桌上
that I was going to sneak onto Charlie's desk.
太好了  是你啊
Oh, good. It's you.
你在这里睡的吗
Did you sleep here?
我女朋友把我甩了  通过电邮
My girlfriend dumped me, uh, in an e-mail.
连当面提分手都不敢
Couldn't even do it face-to-face.
真够懦弱的  是吧
Pretty gutless, huh?
你应该回家  休息一下
Oh, you should go home, get some rest.
我不能回去  太艰难了
I can't go back there. It would be too hard.
太多回忆吗
Mm, too many memories?
不是  我们之前住在我的船上
No, we were living on my boat.
我不知道她把船开哪儿去了
I don't know where she took it.
不发牢骚了  你有什么事
Enough of my whining. What do you need?
我就是  我就过来打个招呼  你好啊
Oh, well, I just -- I just came by to say hi. Hi.
然后顺便用很敞亮的方式告诉你
And also, mm, to tell you in a very gut-ful fashion,
当面提出来
face-to-face,
我一直在考虑的事情
about something that I have been thinking about.
但我真的觉得  我今天不得不
But I do think that, um, I am going to have to leave
提早五分钟下班了
about five minutes early today.
小卡在给一支高中橄榄球队做教练
Uh, Cam is -- is coaching a high-school football game.
-我要去  -你说啥
- I'm in. - What?
我今天肯定是没心情做这些了
Certainly not gonna be able to focus on any of this today.
是的  我需要去看看仪仗队
Yeah, I need a shot of marching bands,
修剪一新的草坪和脸颊粉红的少年们
fresh-cut grass, rosy-cheeked kids.
[美式橄榄球开场前运动员有跑步穿过广告横幅的传统]
他们还会跑步穿过横幅吗
Do they still run through a banner?
-会的  -我超爱那个  超爱
- They do! - I love that. I love that.
所以比赛大概四点开始对吗
OK. So the game's at what, like, 4:00?
我们应该  把那个给我
We should probably -- hey! Give me that.
我
I'm --
这是我的私人号码
This is my private cell.
全世界只有三个人可以打这个号码
Only three people in the whole world use this.
现在是两个人了
Two people.
克莱尔  你为什么
Uh, Claire, is, uh -- is there a reason
没在这张货运单上签字
you didn't sign this shipping form?
不好意思  我立刻签
Oh, no. Sorry. I'll do it now.
现在签有点晚了
Oh, no. No. Now's a little late.
运输公司早上来过了
See, they came in this morning,
没有经理签字什么也做不了
and they can't do a thing without a manager's signature.
所以现在库房里堆了一百块红木板
So now I've got 100 rosewood panels lined up in the warehouse.
以后我希望你能...
On the future, I'd appreciate it --
蒂姆  我觉得你已经说清楚了
Hey, hey, Tim. I think you made your point.
只是个无心之过而已
It was an honest mistake, all right?
-爸  -库房不就是用来
- Dad. - I'm just saying that it's what a warehouse is for,
存东西的嘛
to hold things.
-没什么大不了的  -当然
- Not the end of the world. - Right. Of course.
-抱歉  -我才需要抱歉
- Sorry. - No, I'm sorry.
这是我的错  蒂姆  回见
It's my fault. Bye, Tim. Bye!
爸
Dad!
我早上不是在车上跟你说过了嘛
This is exactly what I was talking about in the car this morning!
我希望他们把我当成同事
I want them to see me like a co-worker,
而不是仗着是老板的女儿
not somebody who's getting special treatment
就拥有特权的人
'cause she's the boss' daughter.
你是不是有点过于敏感了
Is it possible you're being a little oversensitive here?
我才没有  我这是...不是吧
No, I'm not. I'm being -- wow, here? Really?!
这是你给我的
You know, you gave me this.
-看看你当时多可爱  -行了行了
- Look how adorable you were. - Okay. Okay. Okay.
我希望你能认真听进去我说的话
I want you to try really hard to hear what I'm saying.
需要帮助的时候我会找你的
When I need your help, I will ask for it.
但在那以前  不要多管闲事
And until then, just butt out.
你怎么变成这样了
What happened to you?
米勒  你的脚指头看起来有点孤单
Hey, Miller, your toes are looking a little lonely.
你怎么不去拜访一下它们
Why don't you pay them a visit?
教练  为什么要做这么多热身运动
What's with the extra warm-ups, coach?
这帮人一整年都没赢过比赛
These guys haven't won all year.
伙计们你们听到了吗
Did you hear that, team?
米勒同学给你们赢了一个小礼物
Miller just bought you a little present.
我不是抱怨  我只是想知道为什么要
I wasn't complaining. I was just wondering why we have to --
围操场跑一圈
Take a lap!
伯特・拉瓦锡  雷德・斯塔格
Burt Levoisier, Red Stagg,
达琪・庞德
Duckie Pond --
都是这所学校的传奇教练
All coaching legends at this high school,
没人能在第一个赛季拿下超过两场胜利
and none have won more than two games their first season.
今天要是赢了就是我的第三场
I win today, that makes three,
我就会变成有史以来最常胜的新生教练
making me the winningest first-year freshman coach ever.
卢克  罗本病了
Oh, hey, Luke, Reuben's sick,
所以你要当今天的播报员
so I'm gonna need you to be the announcer today.
我怎么可能既计分又播报啊
How am I supposed to keep score and announce at the same time?
跟你既是呆瓜又是笨蛋一样  呆笨
Same way you're a spaz and a dork at the same time, spork.
别这个态度  不过保持这种激情
Okay, lose the attitude, but keep that intensity.
不好意思  裁判
Uh, hey, excuse me, ref.
他们怎么都戴着黑袖标
What's with all the black arm bands?
他们的教练昨晚去世了
Their coach passed away last night.
他病了有一段时间了
He'd been sick for a while.
真不幸  我们还要继续比赛吗
That's terrible. And we're still playing?
这些孩子很坚强
Well, they're tough kids.
罗杰・奈特为高中橄榄球队贡献了一生
Roger Knight lived for high-school football,
他们今天是为他而战
so they're playing this one in his honor.
伙计们  伙计们
Okay, hey, guys! Guys! Guys! Guys!
这是个不幸的消息
Tragic news about coach Knight.
但你们还是要专心打比赛
But you know what? We need to focus up.
表达敬意的机会很多
Plenty of time to pay our respects,
但今天下午不是缅怀奈特教练的时候
but there will be no mourning Knight this afternoon.
-你可真高尚  -是的
- Lot of character over there. - Yep.
-那些孩子一整年都没赢过了  -是的
- Those kids haven't won a game all year. - Uh-huh.
现在还要在他的生日打比赛
And now to have to play on his birthday...
行了 等会儿抛硬币的时候见
Okay, see you at the coin toss.
[房屋出售]
早安[爱尔兰式]
Top of the morning!
搞房地产
Real estate and,
以及从较小的程度上来讲  人生
to a lesser extent, life
都在于坚持
is all about perseverance.
生活总会有不顺
Things go wrong.
钥匙丢了  交易失败  钥匙被乱放
Keys get lost, deals fall through, keys get misplaced.
好多都跟钥匙有关
Uh, a lot of it has to do with keys.
这种时候你就会发现世上有两种人
But that's when you find out there are two types of people --
一种只会盯着锁了的门浪费时间
those who waste time staring at a closed door...
而另一种人会找到一扇窗
and those who find a window.
我正面临第一个"无销售月"的危机
I'm looking at my first month ever without a sale.
有些人也许会放弃
Some people might give up.
但菲尔・邓菲绝对不会
But those people aren't Phil Dunphy.
不
No!
就像我告诉孩子们的
It's like I tell my kids --
保持乐观的心态一切就会如你所愿
keep a positive attitude and things will fall your way.
就像我最爱的红发歌手唱的
As my favorite redhead once sang,
明天太阳会照常升起
the sun will come out tomorrow.
[《小孤儿安妮》是美国著名连载漫画  首次发布于1924年]
那个红发歌手自然是米奇尔
That redhead, of course, was Mitchell,
他当时在向我介绍勇敢的孤儿安妮
introducing me to the plucky orphan Annie...
她用她永不言败的精神
...whose never-say-die attitude pulled this country
把这个国家从大萧条中
out of a little thing called...
解救出来
the great depression.
凡是小女孩能做的事  我也能做
And anything a little girl can do, I can try to do, too.
你们好  欢迎回来
Hey, guys! Welcome back!
请随意参观
Drink it in!
很不错吧
Pretty great, huh?
真高兴你们能在白天过来看房子
Oh, am I glad you guys could see this during the daytime.
真心觉得白天房子更显好看
I really think it shows better like that.
那么
So?
我们就直入主题掏钱给中介费吧
Should we just cut to the chase and pay me my commission?
开玩笑的  中介费不是直接给我的
I'm kidding. You don't pay me directly.
我邓菲的名字里没有"费"这个字
There's no fee in Dun-- Phil.
菲尔  我们有好消息要宣布
Listen, Phil, we've got some great news.
太好了  我的幸运笔呢
I love it! Where's my lucky pen?
我们想当面告诉你
We wanted to tell you this in person.
-我们刚从医院过来的  -我怀孕了
- We just came from the doctor. - I'm pregnant!
天啊  恭喜你们
Oh, my god! You guys!
但我们打算等孩子出生后
Except we decided to put off buying the house
-再考虑买房子  -当然
- until after the baby's born. - Sure.
-六年来我们一直试着要孩子  -当然
- We've been trying for, like, six years. - Sure.
曾经有段时间
For a while there,
我们感觉像在被上帝捉弄
it seemed like the universe was against us.
不可能的
That's ridiculous.
上帝怎么会闲到跟一个人对着干
Why would the universe be against one person?
给你贴张士气贴
Here, have a spirit sticker!
大家都有贴哦
Don't be the only student without one.
我才是这学校的好吗
I actually go to this school!
你还真是路人甲啊
Wow, you really are invisible, huh?
这样再好不过了
I could not be more fine with it.
你特别像一部电影里的角色
You're like that guy from that movie
他希望自己没来过人世
who wishes he was never born.
《生活多美好》
"It's a Wonderful Life".
你嘴上这么说  可真这么想吗
You say that, but do you mean it?
[海豚橄榄球队]
雷德・斯塔格球场赢来了美好的一天
Beautiful day here at Red Stagg field.
开球的是主场作战的44号
Kicking off for the home team is number 44,
杰森・米勒
Jason Miller,
该球员还是长曲棍球以及足球运动员
who also plays lacrosse, soccer, and all the girl parts
还在和死党们一起出演的《歌舞青春》里
when he and his friends act out
扮演了所有女生角色
"High School Musical".
[Girl parts有女性角色和女生私处两个意思]
很可能是他此生看到女生私处的唯一机会
Quite possibly the only girl parts he'll ever see.
海莉
Haley!
你好啊  迪伦
Hey, Dylan!
我都不知道你会过来
I didn't realize you were coming here.
开玩笑呢
Are you kidding?
这地方对我来说像家一样
This place was like a home to me.
就好像我是在家里上学一样
It's like I was homeschooled.
但并不是  我是在学校里上的学
But I wasn't. I was school-schooled.
是么
Were you?
我兜里有六种药
I got six kinds of pills in my pocket,
但来看少年们比赛才是最好的治疗
but this here, all this, this is the best medicine.
我很高兴你感觉好点了
Aw, I'm glad you're feeling better.
是这样的  查理  我
So, Charlie, I --
我是来接莉莉的
I'm here to get Lily.
去叫她前我要跟您说一下今天出的小事故
Oh, before I call her, we had a small issue today.
有个叫帕特里克的男孩说莉莉把他推倒
One of the boys, Patrick, said Lily pushed him down
还要亲他
and tried to kiss him.
不可能  莉莉很高冷的
No, that doesn't sound like Lily.
她可能是在模仿在电视上
She was probably imitating something she saw
或家里看到的情景
on TV or in her family --
一定是在电视上看到的
Ay, it was the TV, yes.
她来了  你看她多可爱啊
Oh, but here she is. She's always so sweet.
再见  帕特里克
Bye, Patrick.
看到了吗  他们只是好朋友
You see? They're just friends.
你笑个屁啊  埃文
What are you laughing at, Evan?
下一个就是你
You're next.
好吧  我会跟她单独谈谈的
Okay, I'm going to talk to her for a little bit.
我跟你说过我把你名字写到那上面吗
Oh, did I ever tell you that I put your name up here?
什么
Huh?
海莉・邓菲的小巨蛋
"Haley Dunphy dome."
真好  你还给我们的专属地点命名了
Aww, you named our special spot?
其实我本来想写"海莉・邓菲请摸我蛋"的
Actually it was supposed to be "Haley Dunphy, do me."
我不太会控制单词间的距离
I'm bad with spacing.
你没那么糟糕啦
Oh, you're not so bad.
中场休息  黑豹队6比0领先海豚队
And that's halftime -- Panthers 6, Dolphins 0.
0分是由杰森・米勒
That zero score by Jason Miller,
骄傲地跑出界造成的
who proudly prances off the field.
别拦我  我要上去踹那小子两脚
Just let me go up there and kick that kid's butt.
行了米勒  你的腿是用来跑的
Knock it off, Miller. I need your leg.
都单腿跪下
Take a knee.
我不知道你们这些小海豚游进了什么陷阱
Now, I don't know what tuna net you Dolphins swam into,
但你们快完蛋了啊
but you are drowning out there!
教练  输了的话有那么糟糕吗
Coach, would it really be such a bad thing if we lost?
-你说什么  -你看看他们
- Beg your pardon? - Look at them, coach.
他们还不够惨吗
Haven't they lost enough already?
也许让他们赢一次
Maybe giving them a win would,
在某种程度上也是成全了我们自己
in a way, be a victory for us, too.
你知道什么对于奈特教练最重要吗
Okay, you know what mattered the most to coach Knight?
照顾那些残疾儿童吗
His work with special-needs kids?
他只不过带了一个孩子去过一次海边而已
Okay, he took one kid to one beach one time.
是橄榄球
Football!
橄榄球才是最重要的
Football is what mattered the most!
他为胜利而活
He lived for competition!
他的信仰是运动员精神  一种气节
He believed in sportsmanship, integrity!
懂吗  我认为  你们大可以上场
Okay? Now, the way I see it, we can roll over
让他们轻松获胜  但那毫无意义
and give them an empty, meaningless victory
他在九泉之下也不会开心的
that he... would hate.
但我们可以自信上场  使出浑身解数
Or we can go out there, leave it all on the field,
让他输也输得心服口服
and be a team he would be proud to lose to.
告诉我  你们是一个人还是一个团队
Now, is this an "I" activity or a "We" activity?!
-团队  -听不见
- We! - What?!
-团队  团队  团队  -这就对了
- We! We! We! We! We! We! - That's right!
你看你们连叫声都像海豚了
Now you sound like dolphins!
你好  蒂姆
Hey, Tim!
接下来三天的发货单给你
I got the next three days of delivery slips
都签好了  不错吧
for you here, signed, huh?
-谢谢你  克莱尔  -没事
- Thanks, Claire. - Yeah.
都签好字了哦
Signed those up good, huh?
多谢
Thanks.
这个  这就是桦木家具啊
So, this is -- this is the, uh, the regency birch?
真不错  好看
Beautiful model. Gorgeous.
你们在这边做的工作很棒
You guys do such good work down here.
我说真的  介意我在它们被送到
Really, you mind if I take her for a spin
展厅之前先参观下吗
before she goes up to the showroom?
-随意  你是老大  -...的闺女
- You're the boss... - 's daughter.
我知道这才是你的心里话
That's what you want to say.
为了运输方便没有装镜子  有道理
Oh, okay. So, no mirror when they're shipping, which makes sense.
而且  也没把手啊
Also have, uh... no handles.
蒂姆
Hey -- hey, Tim?
Hey, Tim!
蒂姆
Tim!
我的天  喂  爸
Oh, god. Yeah, hi, dad.
你好  同事
Hey, co-worker.
我就问问你几点出发去看比赛
Just seeing when you want to leave for the game.
-我们已经迟到了  -马上  马上
- We're late already. - Soon, soon.
我  我在  我在收工了
I'm -- I'm just -- I'm finishing up
我办公室里有点儿文书工作
a little paperwork in my office.
好吧  需要帮忙的话跟我说一声
Okay. Let me know if you need any help.
不用  我不需要你帮忙
No, I do not need your help.
而且我相信我说过了  我希望你
And as I believe I mentioned, I would appreciate it
不要总是严密监视着我
if you were not constantly looking over my shoulder.
拜托  别把我想得那么差劲
Come on. Give me some credit.
我绝对不会那么做的
That's the last thing I would do.
爸  你好像忘了我成功养大了三个孩子
Dad, you seem to forget that I raised three children,
而且在那之前我还有份事业
and I had a career before this.
我做了很多不...
I have done plenty of stuff that does not --
你听到了吗
Do you hear that?
听起来是从库房传来的声音
Sounds like it's coming from the warehouse.
是啊  那是什么声音
Yeah, what even is that?
我确定没什么大不了的
Oh, I'm sure it's nothing.
给你个建议  听不听由你
Uh, one piece of advice -- take it or leave it.
什么
What?
门闩在嵌板的右下方
The latch is under the panel on the right.
我给你买了你喜欢的芥末泡菜
I got you mustard and sauerkraut, just what you like.
你这么友善有点儿吓人
You're being awfully nice,
我刚才可是掀起了一场衣柜龙卷风
considering I started that whole closet-nado.
你仍然是我闺女
Well, you're still my daughter.
我在这里可以这么叫你吧
It's okay I call you that here, right?
可以
Yeah.
听着  我很难像对其他人那样对待你
Listen, it's hard for me to treat you like everyone else.
你是唯一一个被我抱着回家的人
You're the only one I carried home in my arms --
除了去年圣诞派对上的唐雷尔
Except Dontrell, last year's Christmas party.
我几乎是把他从汽车天窗里灌进去的
I pretty much poured him through his sunroof.
但我会尽力
But I'll try.
-谢谢  爸  -你这周末有安排吗
-Thanks, dad.  -You got plans this weekend?
-还没有  怎么了  -很好
- No. Not really. Why? - Good.
明天早上8点到库房
Be at the warehouse, 8:00 tomorrow.
别穿太好的衣服
Wear something you don't care about.
伙计们
Hey, guys.
你好  亲爱的
Hi, honey.
战况如何
What'd I miss?
不太好
Nothing good.
只剩3分钟了  还差6分
We're down by 6 with 3 minutes to play.
他们还是有可能转败为胜的
Well, they could still turn it around.
[The show is not over till the fat lady sings.]
[比赛尚未完全结束之前不能确定胜负]
比赛还没完全结束...  妈呀
Show's not over till the fat -- mama!
米勒震撼人心的凌空一脚
Sensational punt by Miller, who hasn't kicked that high
自从他打破性别界限
since he broke the gender barrier
加入现代舞队以来  从没踢过那么高
and joined our own modern dance troupe.
-你还好吧  亲爱的  -还好
- Are you okay, honey? - Yeah!
一切在于保持心观乐态
It's all about keeping an attitive positude.
乐心观态
Positude attitive.
我们今晚应该去看夜场电影
Hey, we should see a midnight movie tonight,
像以前那样
like old times.
太棒了  我要去
Oh, my god. I am so in!
好  好极了
Cool. Cool.
我11点半左右带着梯子去你家找你吧
I'll come by your house around 11:30 with the ladder?
我不需要从窗子偷偷爬出去了   迪兰
I don't need to climb out of my window anymore, Dylan.
可以早点儿吗  我明天期中考试
Oh, ooh. Can we do it earlier? I have a midterm tomorrow.
我早不了
Oh, I can't do earlier.
我得和几个护士学校的同学见面
I've got to meet up with some classmates from nursing school.
你要当护士吗
You're gonna be a nurse?
是的  我觉得这是我注定的发展方向
Yeah, I figured it was a natural next step.
我一直在用音乐为人们疗伤
I've always healed people with my music,
[drug也表示麻醉剂  毒品]
现在我不过是要用药物做同样的事情
and now I'm just doing the same thing with drugs.
好吧  那就下次吧
Wow. Well, ye-- another time, then.
-好的  -好的
- Yeah. - Yeah.
如果一切顺利的话
Hey, if everything goes well,
也许有一天我会在医院里见到你
maybe one day I'll see you in the hospital.
我很乐意
I'd like that.
最后我终于从衣柜里出来了
So, I finally get out of the closet,
爸就在那里鄙视地看着我
and there's dad looking down at me.
我知道那感觉
Been there.
但是和父亲之间这种微妙的关系
The whole daddy thing, though,
一直是你的一大难题
it's really one of your bigger issues.
至少我的问题是和我亲爸之间的
At least my daddy issues are with my actual daddy.
我不会把我认识的每个权威人物
I don't run around making every authority figure
都当爹一样对待
I meet into a father.
等等
Wait.
你这是什么意思
W-what's that supposed to mean?
米奇尔  拜托
Mitchell, come on.
你为什么还没跟你老板提辞职
Why have you not quit your job yet?
他女朋友刚把他甩了
His girlfriend just broke up with him.
好吧  那你上个星期的借口是什么
Yeah, and what was your excuse last week?
我感冒了
I had a cold.
上上个星期呢
And the week before?
我感觉快要感冒了
I felt a cold coming on.
米奇尔  这封信从你外套里掉出来了
Mitchell, this fell out of your jacket.
能给个解释吗
Care to explain?
我是替一个朋友存放的
I was holding it for a friend.
你要辞职吗
You want to quit?
查理  你  你是个好老板
Charlie, you're -- you're a great boss,
但我接到了另一份工作邀请
but I ju-- I got this other offer,
我真的很想念在法庭上辩论的感觉
and I just really miss the courtroom.
我跟你说实话
Well, I'm not gonna lie to you,
你  真的让我很失望
you're... really letting me down.
我对你有更高的期望
I just expected so much more out of you.
你是我的最喜欢的员工
Ohh. You were my favorite.
天啊
Ohh, god.
也许  我可以在周末给你做事
Um, well, maybe I-I could still do things on the weekends.
不  不  查理  我  我很抱歉
No, no! Charlie, I'm -- I'm sorry.
我  我不干了
I -- I'm done.
你知道吗
You know what?
我不怪你
I don't blame you.
我必须得重新脚踏实地[回到陆地上来]
I have to get back on solid ground.
-彼此彼此  -我比你更需要
- We both do. - Well, I do more.
我住在船上
My house is a boat.
你害我惹上麻烦了
You made me in trouble.
我可没有教你靠扑倒对方来追男孩子
I didn't tell you to sit on a boy until he liked you.
-你就是这么教的  -不是
- Yes-huh. - Nuh-huh.
我不会再听你的建议了
We're not doing this again.
主队申请暂停
Home team calls time-out.
还剩12秒  落后6分
12 seconds left, they're down by 6,
很难摆脱米勒诅咒了
and unable to shake the Miller curse.
我受够了
That's it!
好了  孩子们  最后一搏了
Okay, boys, final play.
让我们使个小诈
Time for a little trickery.
亲爱的  你今天怎么了
Oh, honey. What happened to you today?
上帝给了我一个打击
A cosmic pummeling.
我这笔生意泡汤了
I lost the deal.
如果明天不赶着卖一套
If I don't close on one tomorrow,
这将是我有史以来第一个"无销售月"
it's gonna be my first month ever with no sale.
事实上  这个月没有31号
Actually, there is no 31st this month.
你说什么
What are you talking about?
明天就是1号了
Tomorrow's the first.
亲爱的  抱歉  你还好吗
Honey, I'm sorry. Are you okay?
不  我很不好
No, I'm not okay!
我才发现我已经没有明天了
I just found out there is literally no tomorrow!
我总说  如果坚持等待
You know, I always say if you wait long enough,
幸运之神总会降临
your luck will change?
结果等来的只是一堆垃...
Turns out that's just a big pile of c--
坐稳了  朋友们
Hold on to your hats, folks.
是吗  是的  这就是三路包抄
Are they? They are! It's the triple gull-wing!
这是我排的策略
That's my play!
伍德森假装往右  他又一次假装往右
Woodson fakes right, he fakes right again,
他假装要假装向右  他得分了
he fakes faking right, and he scores!
他们用我的策略得分了
They scored on my play!
-米奇尔说你可以卖房给我  -没错
- Mitchell says you can sell me a house. - Yes, I can!
-菲尔干得好  这是你排的吗  -是
- Good call, Phil. Was that your play?! - Yes, it was!
你表现得太野蛮了  莉莉
You're being too rough, Lily.
你不能看见一个男人
You cannot just see a guy and,
就这么上去亲他  懂吗
mwah, kiss him like that, okay?
你可以  你可以的
Yes, you can! Yes, you can!
米勒出局了  曼尼  你是替补开球手
Okay! Okay! Miller's out. Manny, you're my backup kicker.
我需要你上去拿下这脚球
I need you to go out there and nail this.
即使我踢不中
Although if I miss it,
平局何尝不是一个完美的方式
wouldn't a tie be a perfect way to --
曼尼  够了
Manny, enough!
你不能夺走我的胜利
You are not gonna take away my victory!
我是说  你们的胜利
I mean -- I mean, your victory.
好吗
Okay?
曼尼  抱歉  我不该吼你的
Manny, I'm sorry. I should not have yelled at you.
你尽管过去  做你觉得正确的事
You can go out there and do whatever feels right.
好吗  不管怎样我都支持你
Okay? I support you no matter what.
准备  发射
Hut! Hut! Hike!
我赢了  我赢了  我是说我们赢了
I won! I won! I mean, we won!
我们赢了  我们赢了
We won! We won!
抱歉  女士
Ooph! Sorry, ma'am.
女士  英语课我就坐你边上
Ma'am? I sit next to you in English.
我好像把手机落在看台下面了
Hey, I think I dropped my phone under the bleachers.
和我去拿一下好吗
Come get it with me?
找到了
Found it.
太好了  世界又平静了
Great, and world order is restored.
-可以回家了吗  -可以
- Can we go home now? - Yeah. Okay.
看  这是什么
Oh, hey, what's that?
艾丽克斯・邓菲的小巨蛋
"Alex Dunphy dome?"
我觉得是"艾丽克斯・邓菲请摸我蛋"
Uh, I think it says "Alex Dunphy, do me."
谁会写这种东西
Ugh, who would write something like that?
不知道
No idea.
需要我帮你擦掉吗
Hey, you want me to scratch it out?
不  我是说  太晚了
No! I mean, pfft, too late now.
已经写在那了  就这样吧
If it's out there, it's out there.
小冠军
Hey, champ.
不去和大家庆祝一下吗
Aren't you gonna go celebrate with your team?
去  等会就去
Yeah, in a minute.
你本来是不打算踢中的  对吗
You meant to miss the kick, didn't you?
我搞砸了
I blew it.
十次我有九次踢不中
I could miss that kick nine out of ten times.
怎么真正需要踢不中的时候却踢中了呢
Why couldn't I miss it when it counted?
让我来问问你
Let me ask you something.
当球穿过球门
That ball sails through the uprights,
队员们举着你走出球场
your team carries you off the field.
那感觉怎样
How does that feel?
-说啊  -感觉很好
- Come on. - Good.
成为团队一员很开心
It's fun being part of a team.
成为大英雄更是开心
And it's really fun being the hero.
所以我觉得  你是特意要踢中的
So I think you made that kick on purpose.
听我说
And listen.
你现在也许还不想承认
I don't think you're willing to admit it yet,
但在每个人性深处
but somewhere underneath all that humanity,
都有一个争强好胜者  抱歉
there's a competitor -- sorry.
都有一个争强好胜者  曼尼
There's a competitor, and, Manny,
这没什么不对的
there's nothing wrong with that.
没什么不对
Nothing.
谢谢你  教练
Thanks, coach.
想去吃点比萨吗
You want to go eat some pizza?
-当然  -我也要来点
- Sure. - Me, too.
你觉得他们会改用你的名字来命名球场吗
Hey, you think someday they might name this field after you?
你并不是第一个
Well, you're not the first person
这么想的人
to think along those lines.
早些时候  就有人在职工卫生间写上
Earlier today, someone in the faculty bathroom
"卡梅隆・塔克的小巨蛋"这个名字了
was messing around with the phrase "Cameron Tucker dome."
我刚卖出了镇上最贵的房子
Just sold the most expensive house in town,
房都没看  全部现金付清
sight unseen, all cash.
-怎样  -我为你骄傲  老爸
- How 'bout that? - I'm proud of you, dad.
邓菲一家今天都很棒
Pretty great day for all the Dunphys.
然后我说"米歇尔  你真的相信那些
And then I said, "Michelle, do you honestly believe
愚蠢的谣言吗"
every stupid rumor you hear?"
你还没听说吗
Oh, you haven't heard?
很明显  我的某一个前任...
Well, apparently, one of my exes is just, like...
蒂姆  真抱歉你受伤了
Tim, I -- I am so sorry that you got hurt,
我会查出问题所在
and I will get to the bottom of it,
但我怀疑是竞争对手故意破坏
but I suspect it was sabotage by the competition,
很可能是"衣柜衣柜衣柜衣柜"公司
maybe Closets, Closets, Closets, Closets.
还不错  有点肿  有点像你看完
Not too bad, a little puffy, kind of like your eyes were
《海底总动员》之后哭红的双眼  米勒
when you saw "Finding Nemo," Miller.
我不是说了吗  要有乐观的心态
Like I said -- positive attitude.